Timothy P. Allen

Sheffield, UK +44 7581 399128 | tallenp@me.com http://uk.linkedin.com/in/tallenp

A highly motivated software engineer with experience in a broad variety of technologies. Most recent projects include development of CI/CD solutions for company Azure resources. A quick thinker and adaptable, likes a challenge and seeks opportunities to learn. Comfortable working with international teams across time zones where efficient communication is key.

KEY SKILLS

Broad development knowledge including Java, Kubernetes and Python Strong analytical skills and level-headed problem solver Technically fluent with current software development tools Industry aware and customer focused

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer | 3Squared | Sheffield, UK

2019 - Present

Leading the introduction of new CI/CD technologies and processes across the company. These include Azure resource management with Terraform and automated build pipelines with TeamCity and Octopus Deploy. Operating additional support services for internal teams and remote clients.

Senior Software Engineer | Refinitiv | Nottingham, UK

2018 - 2019

Worked in a DevOps role, using technologies such as Jenkins, AWS Lambda and Kubernetes. Involved in projects to automate and maximise the efficiency of other teams across the organisation.

Technology Graduate | Thomson Reuters | Nottingham, UK

2017 - 2018

Introduction to a Dev team and cloud technologies. Role included creating automated CI/CD systems for cloud deployment. Promoted from this role to a Senior Software Engineer when the program ended.

Quality Engineer Intern | Thomson Reuters | Nottingham, UK

2015 - 2016

Worked within a QA team on a Thomson Reuters owned application. Responsibilities included automated test development in C#, maintaining the testing framework and running test regression.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming | Agile Methodologies | Java | Docker | Kubernetes | CI/CD | AWS | Azure | Terraform | TeamCity | Bash Script | Python | JavaScript | HMTL 5 | Git | Linux | GoCD | Jenkins | Swift | JIRA | Maven

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Tester Foundation Level | ISTQB

2018

EDUCATION

Sheffield Hallam University BEng (Hons) Software Engineering	2013 - 2017
Heanor Gate Science College A Level Maths Physics Product Design	2012
Heanor Gate Science College GSCE Including A in Maths & B in English	2010

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

Scuba Diving Club Chairman (2014) and Training Officer (2018)

Scuba Diving Instructor

Volunteer Expedition to Morocco with World Challenge Org.

Chief Scout Gold Award with Scouts

INTERESTS

Scuba Diving | Travel | Music | Photography | DIY